<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. S Balakrishnan</title>
    <description>Assistant Professor, Sri Krishna College of Engineering, Coimbator</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 21:32:23 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 21:32:23 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Utrecht Degrowth Symposium: From circular economy to circular society</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I helped my colleagues at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uu.nl/en/research/copernicus-institute-of-sustainable-development&quot;&gt;Copernicus Institute of Sustainable Development&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ontgroei.nl/&quot;&gt;Dutch degrowth platform&lt;/a&gt; to organize the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uu.nl/en/events/online-utrecht-degrowth-symposium-from-circular-economy-to-circular-society&quot;&gt;2nd Utrecht Degrowth Symposium: From circular economy to circular society&lt;/a&gt;. In this symposium, we connected to stakeholders from academic and non-academic institutions to discuss the holistic societal transformations needed to address the pressing socio-ecological crisis of the 21st century on climate change and resource depletion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 22:15:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/circular-society-symposium/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/circular-society-symposium/</guid>
        
        <category>climate action</category>
        
        <category>sustainability</category>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>UYA Climate Pledge</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with Liesbeth van de Grift and Erik van Sebille, we presented the UYA &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uu.nl/en/news/the-utrecht-young-academy-appeals-to-uu-leadership-at-pathways-to-sustainability-conference-2020&quot;&gt;Climate Action Pledge&lt;/a&gt; to the President of the Executive Board of Utrecht Univesity, Anton Pijpers. We appealed to the Utrecht University leadership to step up sustainability ambitions and sign a pledge. The UYA Climate Action Pledge embodies both the acknowledgement of the high risk of our current national policies and the urgency of action, as well as key suggestions for an adequate response to the climate crisis. The president stated the board’s support for our actions and adn that they will adopt the pledge and concomitant actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://sanlifaez.github.io/images/UYA_climate_pledge.png&quot; alt=&quot;UYA climate pledge&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 21:45:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020/UYA-climate-pledge/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020/UYA-climate-pledge/</guid>
        
        <category>climate action</category>
        
        <category>sustainability</category>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Spin-off company</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aquicarattino.com/&quot;&gt;Aquiles Carattino&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://nascentventures.nl/&quot;&gt;Nascent Ventures&lt;/a&gt;, we recieved a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nwo.nl/onderzoek-en-resultaten/programmas/take-off/toekenningen/2018/2018-17466&quot;&gt;take-off grant&lt;/a&gt; for characterization of nanoparticles in solution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An NWO Take-off grant has been awarded for commercialization of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nanoepics.github.io/research/&quot;&gt;nanoCET platform&lt;/a&gt;, a device that can measure the size, concentration and charge of nanoparticles while in solution. With a commercial version of this device, we hope to accommodate a very large group of researchers in different fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an extract form the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uu.nl/en/news/take-off-grant-for-characterization-of-nanoparticles-in-solution&quot;&gt;UU news item about this grant&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The novelty about nanoCET is the fact that samples are investigated in a solution, which keeps particles in their natural three-dimensional shape. The device can thus optically track nanoparticles like single viral proteins. It consists of an optical fiber with a channel smaller than a wavelength of light. Inside this channel, light runs through an aqueous sample that contains nanoparticles. The light is scattered, and nanoparticles are detected by the microscope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the NWO Take-off grant of 40,000 euros, the Light in Complex Systems group of the Debye Institute for Nanomaterials Science will be able to do a feasibility study in the first half of 2019, investigating the expected success of spin-off company. The invention itself was done in 2015, when Sanli Faez worked at Leiden University. Watch the &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/nanoCET&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; made by Harvard University at that time.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 03:09:32 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/spin-off-company/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/spin-off-company/</guid>
        
        <category>applications</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Summer-in-lab in Oxford</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past two month, I had the great pleasure of doing experiments with &lt;a href=&quot;http://kukura.chem.ox.ac.uk/home&quot;&gt;Philipp Kukura’s group&lt;/a&gt; at the department of Chemistry in Oxford. This was an opportunity created by the superb hospitality of Philipp and his group members, and me not taking enough vacation days for the previous two years. Spending most of my time in the lab and getting my hands busy with some of the most sensitive optical microscopes in the world was a remarkable experience. I am no stranger to sensitive microscopes, but the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aragobio.com/&quot;&gt;iSCAMS technology&lt;/a&gt;, with its unique combination of sensitivity and ease of operation, is a real breakthrough. Each week I saw some visiting researchers coming with their samples in ice-boxes and at the end of the day leaving with a smile on their face because of the incredible measurements they could take in a single day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Philipp generously allowed me to play with their setups and try some crazy ideas. We were quite lucky that a couple of those ideas worked really well, or perhaps they weren’t crazy enough. Crazy or not, the common interests we discovered this summer will hopefully be the beginning of some fruitful collaboration between our teams at Oxford and Utrecht.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also spent several weekends rowing in an eight on the Thames under a pleasantly clear sky. For the three weeks that Bahar and Soline joined me, we could spend ample good time together and with friends, playing, punting, and sight-seeing. That couldn’t possibly be as pleasant if we did not have that exceptionally sunny weather and the company of our very good friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oii.ox.ac.uk/people/taha-yasseri/&quot;&gt;Taha&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 03:09:32 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/summer-in-lab-in-Oxford/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/summer-in-lab-in-Oxford/</guid>
        
        <category>research</category>
        
        <category>collaboration</category>
        
        <category>ideas</category>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Four undergraduate projects start today</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Four new projects related to various aspects of electrokinetic tracking will start today. Lorenzo Peres is going to make a microfluidic channel with embedded electrodes. This channel hopefully allows him to measure surface charge of the channel as function of flow. Peter Speets will also use a similar channel to study growth and shrinkage of protein aggregates using nanoparticle tracking and resonant light scattering. Milo Colaris will use an acoustic levitator to measure the viscosity of a floating droplet of a suspension as it dries. The method he develps will be later applied to very small droplets trapped with an optical tweezers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a collaboration with Amir Raoof from the faculty of Geosciences, Qianjing Tang with make a new optical setup for studying flow in planar microchannels using a technique similar to Fluorecence Recovery after Photobleaching. In this setup, we should be able to study flow in centimeter-wide networks with micrometer resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 14:50:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/four-new-undergraduate-projects-start/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/four-new-undergraduate-projects-start/</guid>
        
        <category>students</category>
        
        <category>teaching</category>
        
        <category>electrokinetic tracking</category>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>U-Talent project with a DIY-microscope</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last September, 4 students from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://u-talent.nl/&quot;&gt;U-Talent&lt;/a&gt; program performed their final project in our group. They used a DIY-microscope, previously developed in the bachelor project of Kevin Namink, to measure the Brownian motion of nanoparticles. Their goal was to measure the viscosity of the liquid by determination of the Diffusion constant. &lt;em&gt;De Odysee van een deeltje in een suspensie&lt;/em&gt; was presented with remarkable confidence by
Lucas Abbenhuis, Evert Sarolea, Samuel Klumpers, and Jip Ridderbos during the final &lt;a href=&quot;https://u-talent.nl/thesis-b/&quot;&gt;thesis-symposium&lt;/a&gt; in an almost full classroom. Here is a shot from the back of the room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://sanlifaez.github.io/images/20180109_utalent_presenting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Lucas Abbenhuis, Evert Sarolea, Samuel Klumpers, Jip Ridderbos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2018 21:50:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/UTalent-student-present-their-project/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/UTalent-student-present-their-project/</guid>
        
        <category>students</category>
        
        <category>teaching</category>
        
        <category>openscience</category>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Blogging about Voice of UYA Podcasts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was invited to write blogs on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dub.uu.nl/en/&quot;&gt;Utrecht University news site&lt;/a&gt; about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/utrechtyoungacademy&quot;&gt;podcasts I make&lt;/a&gt; for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.uu.nl/en/research/utrecht-young-academy&quot;&gt;Utrecht Young Academy&lt;/a&gt;. In &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dub.uu.nl/en/blog/do-not-take-it-face-value&quot;&gt;my first blogpost&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Do not take it at the face value&lt;/strong&gt;, I introduce the &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/utrechtyoungacademy/voice-of-uya-ron-dotsch&quot;&gt;third podcast episode with Ron Dotsch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ron Dotsch is a psychologist that has studied human perception of others’ faces for more than a decade. For his research he heavily uses technologies such as virtual reality and computer-generated modelling. He tells me how we adjust our interaction with people based on less than a second of looking at their faces. When meeting strangers, we tend to judge their characteristics, such as trustworthiness, sexual orientation, or political views, based on a very short glance. He also tells me that these kinds of judgment are mostly wrong. Research shows that for guessing the political orientation correctly seeing one’s face does not help any more than knowing age, skin color, and gender.
Ron has experienced both making it into the system and breaking away from it. Last summer he resigned from his tenured university position as an associate professor of behavioral psychology. He has left academia to work in a company. I curiously wanted to know why and I could not read it from his face.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 04:14:12 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/introducing-uya-podcasts/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/introducing-uya-podcasts/</guid>
        
        <category>podcast</category>
        
        <category>academia</category>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Migrating to GitHub pages</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After several years of happily administring my personal pages with the mediawiki software on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sanlifaez.com&quot;&gt;my old website&lt;/a&gt; and less happily paying the ever-increasing hosting fees, I thought of migrating to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;github pages&lt;/a&gt;. Those payments for hosting fees are much better spent if I donate them to the Wikimedia Foundation, and their exciting recent initiative &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wikitribune.com/&quot;&gt;the wikitribune&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After looking around for a while, I finally chose the beautiful &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyll-themes.com/uno/&quot;&gt;Uno&lt;/a&gt; theme, made by Josh Gerdes, and here we are, testing the new website with the first post. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. It turns to be very easy to set up a beautiful multi-page website, once you get hold of a few basic rules. Shout out to all the open-source community and their wonderful collective achievements.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 17:14:12 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/migrating-to-github/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/migrating-to-github/</guid>
        
        <category>open-source</category>
        
        
        <category>updates</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
